So far, most of the numbers we've been working with have been whole numbers or integers.
到目前为止 我们一直处理的数字都是整数或整型
However, as you may have noticed other types of numbers do exist in Python.
但是 你可能注意到了其他类型的数字也存在于 Python 中
Here, dividing one integer by another gives us a number that isn't an integer 0.75.
这里 用一个整数除以另一个整数的结果是非整数 0.75
In Python and computing in general,
在 Python 及一般的计算机语言中
we represent such a number as a float,
我们将此类数字表示为浮点型
which is short for floating point number.
它是浮点数字的简称
A float is a real number that uses
浮点型是使用小数点
a decimal point to allow numbers with fractional values.
来表示分数值的实数
Even if one integer divides another exactly,
即使一个整数能够除尽另一个整数
the result will be a float.
结果也是浮点型
The int and float are actually two kinds of data types.
整型和浮点型实际上是两种数据类型
In Python, every object you encounter will have a type.
在 Python 中 你遇到的每个对象都是一个类型
An object's type defines which operators and
对象类型定义了哪些运算符和函数
functions will work on that object and how they work.
适合该对象以及计算原理
You can check the type of any object directly using the built-in function type.
你可以使用内置函数 type() 直接检查任何对象的类型
Here you can see that the type of a number without
从这里可以看出 在 Python 中
a decimal and a number with a decimal are different in Python.
没有小数和有小数的数字类型不一样
To make an int,
要使用整型
just give a whole number without a decimal point.
只需提供没有小数点的整数
Here is an int.
这是一个整型
To make a float, include a decimal point.
要使用浮点型 则包含小数点
If the number itself is actually a whole number,
如果数字本身是整数
that's okay, you don't even have to put anything after the decimal point.
没关系 你甚至不需要在小数点后提供任何数字
These are both floats.
这两个都是浮点型
An operation involving an int and a float always produces a float.
涉及整型和浮点型的运算始终生成浮点型数字
Sometimes, you might need to manually convert one numeric type to another.
有时候 你可能需要手动地将一种数字类型转换为另一种类型
And you can do that by constructing new objects of those types with int and float.
为此 你可以使用 int 和 float 构建这些类型的新对象
When we convert a float to an int,
当我们将浮点型转换为整型时
the part of the number after the decimal point
小数点后的部分会被截断
is cut off which means that no rounding occurs.
也就是不进行四舍五入
49.7 is cut to 49.
49.7 被截成 49
4.0 calculated from 16 divided by 4 is cut to 4.
16 除以 4 后得出的 4.0 被截成 4
Converting from int to float adds decimal zero to the end of the number.
从整型转换为浮点型时 会在数字后面添加小数点和 0
So, we've seen Python's two main numeric types:
我们见到了 Python 的两大主要数字类型
integers and floating point numbers. What are they good for?
整数和浮点数 它们有什么作用？
There are many times when you might need to count items or
很多时候 你可能需要数条目的数量
need to rely on the result of a computation being an integer.
或需要计算结果是整数
For example, let's say you want to count how many people showed up at your dinner party.
例如 假设你想数一下晚宴上来了多少人
You can't count 0.47 of a person,
不能将人数统计成 0.47 人
so you use an integer.
因此使用整数
If what you're working on isn't necessarily a whole number,
如果你要处理的数字不一定是整数
a float is the type you're looking for.
则需要使用浮点型
For example, let's say you made five pies for
例如 假设你为晚宴做了 5 个派
your dinner party and you want to keep track of the amount of pie left.
你想要记录剩下多少派
People usually take one-sixth of a slice.
人们通常会吃 1/6
Once one slice is taken,
拿走一片后
you're down to 4.83 pies,
剩下 4.83 片
so you use a float.
因此使用浮点型
Floating point numbers are approximations of the numbers they're opposed to represent.
浮点数字是应该要表示的数字的近似值
This is necessary because floats can represent an enormous range of numbers.
有必要这样 因为浮点型可以表示的数字范围很广
So, in order to fit numbers in computer memory,
因此 为了在计算机内存中存下数字
Python must use approximations.
Python 必须使用近似值
This trade off can sometimes have surprising results.
这种近似方法有时候会产生意外的结果
Because the float or approximation for 0.1 is actually slightly more than zero 0.1,
因为 0.1 的浮点值或近似值比 0.1 稍微大些
when add several of them together we can see a difference
当我们将好几个这种数字相加
between the mathematically correct answer and the one that Python creates.
会发现数学上正确的答案与 Python 创建的结果有差别
In most contexts, these small differences are
在大多数情况下 这种小小的差别影响不大
irrelevant but it's important to know that they're there.
但是必须知道存在这种差别
You can read more about this in the instructor notes.
你可以在讲师注释中了解更多信息